# Muhammad Aqib Saleem

House# SN-622, Madina Market, Dhok Kala Khan, Rawalpindi. | 03319283006 | aqib.saleem192@gmail.com

#### **Summary**

I am an innovative software engineer with 3 years of experience managing all aspects of the development process for current Employer. During this time, I have had the opportunity to serve as a member of software development teams, through which I was able to develop strong communication skills as well as a good appreciation for the collective strength of a workgroup. UAT of different projects allowed me to interact with international clients and learn client handling skills.

#### **Experience**

## SOFTWARE ENGINEER E-COMMERCE (MAGENTO 2.X)| EVAMP & SAANGA | $2^{ND}$ JULY 2018 - PRESENT

- · Development and enhancement of Magento 2 based applications/websites.
- · Customized Magento 2 inherent features based on client needs.
- · Create custom modules within Magento2.
- · Created custom API's in Magento2.
- · Magento 2 theme customization.
- · Magento 2 multi store management.
- · Magento 2 custom configuration for modules.
- · Migration of customers and catalog from Magento (1.x) to Magento (2.x) on "Korek Project".
- · Contributed in highly scalable project "Jazz World APP" (handling millions of customers) as a backend developer. Implement custom business logic and integrate with backend APIs
- · Create custom theme/configuration, content types, block, view in Drupal8.

#### WEB APPLICATION TRAINING | ARETE APPS | 1ST NOV 2017 - 30TH APRIL 2018

- · During web application training I have learn Php and WordPress.
- · Work on two different WordPress website customization.

#### INTERNSHIP| ATTORNEY GENERAL OFFICE (AGFP) | 1ST APRIL 2016 – 30TH APRIL 2017

- · During one year internship I was working on different task.
- · Provide support on installation of different software's and operating systems.
- · Maintain online records of library and attendance management system.
- · Update content on the official website on Attorney-e-General Office.

### **Projects**

- MTN Marketplace
- · Korek Mobile Application Iraq
- · Jazz World Application
- · Board of Investment (BOI)

- Pakistan Centre for Philanthropy (PCP)
- · Metropolitan Academy of Arts and Design
- · Auto Insurance Worx

#### **Skills**

- · Magento (2.x)
- · PHP
- · MySQL
- · JQuery
- · Drupal 8

- · JavaScript
- · HTML
- · CSS
- · Ajax
- · WordPress

#### **Education**

#### MASTER OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY | 2013-2016

Quaid I Azam University, Islamabad.

#### BSC | 2010-2012

University of Gujrat, Gujrat.

#### ICS | 2008-2010

BISE Gujranwala

#### Languages

· English · Urdu · Punjabi

#### **Interests**

- · Exploring and troubleshooting the Computers/Computer networks
- Cricket
- · Web Surfing
- Movies